Guide to the Dianne Hunt papers, 1976-1995 MS2143
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dianne Hunt papers
1976-1995
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Hunt, Dianne Patricia
MS2143
2 Linear Feet
Collection includes flyers, posters, postcards, press releases, programs, two photographs, and a bit of correspondence. The material relates to the productions undertaken by members of the dance community in Washington D.C. from 1976-1990.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Dianne Hunt donated this material to Gelman library in 2003 and 2005.
Historical or Biographical Note
Dianne Hunt, a dancer and choreographer has worked in the Washington D.C. area for more than 20 years. Along with Ron Paul, she founded the modern dance company, Upright Vertebrates in 1984. At around this same time, she also led the company Dianne Hunt and Dancers. Dianne began her dance training in Minneapolis while studying fine arts at the University of Minnesota. Her training includes classical ballet and pointe. She completed her MA in dance at GW with an oral history memoir of Erika Thimey. Since 1981, she produced her own choreography regularly in Washington and Baltimore and on tour in Minnesota, Virginia, and Massachusetts. During her career, Dianne taught at numerous institutions in the Washington area including GW and from 1981-83, Dianne was on the faculty at Shenandoah College and Conservatory teaching dance composition, history, technique, repertory and improvisation. In 2000, noted dancer, teacher and choreographer Erika Thimey, who lives in Virginia and celebrated her 90th birthday in March 2000, published A Life of Dance, A Dance of Life, an autobiography/biography written with Dianne Hunt.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection includes flyers, posters, postcards, press releases, programs, two photographs, and a bit of correspondence. The material relates to the productions undertaken by members of the dance community in Washington D.C. from 1976-90. This material includes programs and flyers for productions from noted dancers, dance companies, and choreographers in the Washington D.C. area including Lucinda Weaver Hall, Lonna Wilkinson, Jack Guidone, Dianne Hunt, Jan Taylor, Wendy Woodson, Susan Le Mieux, and Ron Paul, Upright Vertebrates, Maida Withers and the Dance Construction Company, the Paul Taylor Dance Company, Diane Floyd and Saturday Company, The Dance Place, The Dance Co-op, and Merce Cunningham Dance Company.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series: Metropolitan Dance Association, Dance Coalition, Dance Directions, and Dance performances materials.
Dance; Dancers; Modern dance; Washington (D.C.); Photographs; Hunt, Dianne Patricia; Metropolitan Dance Association; Woodson, Wendy; Withers, Maida; Paul, Ron (choreographer)
- Metropolitan Dance Association, 1966-1995; MS2143 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains correspondence, financial records, a directory, membership material, fundraising and loan documentation. The material is dated from 1966-95.
  The Metropolitan Dance Association (MDA) began in 1953 as the Modern Dance Council of Washington, D.C. The organization name change adopted in September 1979 reflected a shift to document local and regional dance heritage. Annual meetings of the Association featured performances and presentations by and about the regional dance community.
  Among the activities undertaken by the Association was the Choreographers Showcase begun in 1958 to provide artistic opportunities to less experienced choreographers. The showcase was renamed Dance Showcase in 1978. The Association also sponsored a loan fund to provide financial assistance to dancers, choreographers, teachers and others in support of project relating to the advancement of contemporary dance in the Washington metropolitan area. Responding to the needs of its members, the Association contracted the services of a health and insurance organization to provide much needed insurance to those who might not have otherwise been able to afford it. The Associations' commitments to dancers, dance performance and dance heritage was recognized in its receipt of several grants.
  - MDA Loan Fund [Modern Dance Council], 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - MDA Modern Dance Council Grants History, 1966-1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MDA Certificate of exemption, 09/15/1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - MDA [Modern Dance Council] Cafritz grant, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MDA ICC Concert, flyers, programs, WPA, Marvin, T.J. Dance Place, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - MDA ICC Concert, T.J. Theatre, 01/1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - MDA 1980 1st Awards ceremony St. Mark's Church, 04/13/1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MDA 1981 Awards ceremony (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MDA records, 10/1981-11/1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - MDA Awards ceremony, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Support Center: Accounting presentation documents, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - MDA Dance directory, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MDA Accomplishments; Board of Directors, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Washington D.C. Dance Alliance [MDA], 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The Support Center: Fundamentals in Management presenters John Boruff and Rene Johnson, 10/02/1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Support Center: Bookkeeping and Financial Management II presenter Lynn Bock, 10/16/1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - MDA Committee for the Survival of Dance in Washington, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Membership --welcome letter-new [MDA], 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - MDA Letter to Community, 02/22/1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Loan--MDA Deborah Riley, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - MDA Fundraising, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Support Center: Four-Step Public Relations Process [course materials], undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Dance Coalition, 1980-1994; MS2143 Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains correspondence, membership lists, contracts, and financial records. The material dates from 1980-94. The Dance Coalition was a non-profit corporation governed by a Board of Directors. It was conceived of as an umbrella organization for dancers and performers and functioned as a "home base" for several different artists. Membership was structured in two categories. Regular and associate memberships were available to choreographers, actors, dancers and people interested in movement arts. The Coalition offered rehearsal rates and opportunities to participate in group concerts and to produce events in its studio theater. The group rented space at St. James Parish on Capitol Hill.
  - Dance Coalition, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Dance Coalition Member contracts (current), 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Dance Coalition Membership and Financial records, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Dance Coalition St. James contracts 1980-, 1980-1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Dance Directions, 1985-1986; MS2143 Series 3; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains programs, correspondence, flyers, reports, financial records, meeting minutes, and press releases. This material relates to the dance festival Washington Dance Directions. The series covers the festival for 1985 and 1986. Dance Directions was the opportunity for audiences in Washington D.C. to view a variety of modern dance performances as a sample of the type of work produced and performed in Washington, D.C. The performances featured a collaboration of local choreographers and dance companies to promote their work in the District of Columbia.
  - Dance Direction 85 report, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Dance Directions, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - DD 86 Financial, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - DD 86 Fundraising, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Dance Directions '86 meeting minutes, 03/16/1986-06/08/1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - DD 86 Participants Jobs, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - DD 86 photocopies P.R., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Dance performances materials, 1980-1990; MS2143 Series 4; 1.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains photographs, flyers, programs, posters, newspaper articles, and resumes. The material relates to the productions and work of the dance community in Washington, D.C. from 1980-90. The choreographers and dancers include Lucinda Weaver Hall, Lonna Wilkinson, Jack Guidone, Dianne Hunt, Jan Taylor, Susan Le Mieux, and Ron Paul and the companies include Upright Vertebrates, Maida Withers and the Dance Construction Company, the Paul Taylor Dance Company, Diane Floyd and Saturday Company, The Dance Place, The Dance Co-op, and Merce Cunningham Dance Company.
  - Axolotl/Jack Guidone Metamorphasis, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dance performance materials Dianne Hunt and Dancers and Upright Vertebrates, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Dance performance materials photograph Jan Taylor, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Dance performances Lucinda Weaver Hall, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Dance performance materials photograph Wendy Woodson, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Dance performances, 1980-1990 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dance performances, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Posters, undated (Box 2)
  - Dance performances posters, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)